<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>paglaadmin &#8211; Dance</title>
	<atom:link href="httpwww.dance.uw.edu/author/paglaadmin/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>httpwww.dance.uw.edu</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 16:06:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Pentagon eyes missile testing role for Australia</title>
		<link>httpwww.dance.uw.edu/pentagon-eyes-missile-testing-role-for-australia/</link>
					<comments>httpwww.dance.uw.edu/pentagon-eyes-missile-testing-role-for-australia/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[paglaadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 16:06:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[International]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">httpwww.dance.uw.edu/?p=18</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Australia could be a testing ground for US hypersonic and other long-range precision weapons under the AUKUS pact, a top Pentagon official told AFP on Wednesday. US Secretary of the Army Christine Wormuth said Australia&#8217;s contribution to the three-way AUKUS agreement, which includes Britain, &#8220;doesn&#8217;t always have to be dollars&#8221;. The pact was signed in [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Australia could be a testing ground for US hypersonic and other long-range precision weapons under the AUKUS pact, a top Pentagon official told AFP on Wednesday.<br />
US Secretary of the Army Christine Wormuth said Australia&#8217;s contribution to the three-way AUKUS agreement, which includes Britain, &#8220;doesn&#8217;t always have to be dollars&#8221;. The pact was signed in late 2021 and is seen as a way of countering China&#8217;s growing clout in the Asia-Pacific region.<br />
Work under AUKUS has so far focused on supplying Australia with nuclear-powered submarines, a fleet capable of travelling stealthily over vast distances and striking foes at long range.<br />
But the pact is increasingly focused on developing advanced capabilities such as long-range precision firing, artificial intelligence and hypersonic weapons.<br />
Wormuth said Australia could be a proving ground for these weapons.<br />
&#8220;One thing Australia has in spades is long distances and relatively unpopulated land, &#8221; she told AFP in a telephone interview from Washington.<br />
&#8220;A challenge for us in the United States when it comes to hypersonics or even some of our things like the precision strike missile &#8212; which is not a hypersonic weapon but has very long ranges in some of its increments &#8212; for us to find open spaces in the United States where we can actually test these weapons, it&#8217;s a challenge.</p>
<p>&#8220;Australia obviously has a tremendous amount of territory where that testing is a little bit more doable &#8212; so I think that&#8217;s a unique thing, as an example, that the Australians bring to the table. &#8221;<br />
China has denounced the AUKUS pact as undermining peace in the region &#8212; a charge that Washington, Canberra and London reject.<br />
But critics have also asked whether it is truly cooperative, or whether the United States, because of its size and overwhelming military power, will dominate.<br />
Wormuth said she expected the two smaller partners to pitch in and &#8220;have skin in this game &#8212; and they do&#8221;.<br />
&#8220;The sense I got certainly from talking to senior Australian officials is they&#8217;re not doing this to make us happy, they&#8217;re not doing this just for fun, &#8221; said the Pentagon official, who visited Australia last week for the Talisman Sabre multinational military exercise.<br />
&#8220;They&#8217;re doing this because they see it as in their own national interest in terms of being able to meet the different challenges that they see in the theatre. &#8221;</p>
<p>&#8216;Prohibitively expensive&#8217;<br />
Facing Russia&#8217;s war in Europe, threats from North Korea and a more bellicose China, the United States has sought to bolster its defence alliances and put more advanced capabilities into the hands of allies like Australia, Ukraine and Taiwan.</p>
<p>For much of the Cold War, it was Washington&#8217;s policy to be able to fight two major wars at once.<br />
Wormuth admitted that today, budget constraints, US public opinion and the relative strength of Russia and China make such a doctrine impossible.<br />
&#8220;I think there is a recognition that when you look at the size of our military, when you look at the size of the defence budget that the American taxpayer is willing to pay for, we. . . don&#8217;t plan to fight more than one major war at a time, &#8221; she said.<br />
Instead, the United States hopes its alliance and nuclear arsenal will &#8220;discourage opportunistic aggression&#8221;.<br />
&#8220;Given the sophistication of the Russian military and the Chinese military today, to try to size our military to hypothetically handle two wars at a time would be prohibitively expensive&#8221;.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>httpwww.dance.uw.edu/pentagon-eyes-missile-testing-role-for-australia/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Colombia ‘dreaming big’ as they plot England downfall at Women’s World Cup</title>
		<link>httpwww.dance.uw.edu/colombia-dreaming-big-as-they-plot-england-downfall-at-womens-world-cup/</link>
					<comments>httpwww.dance.uw.edu/colombia-dreaming-big-as-they-plot-england-downfall-at-womens-world-cup/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[paglaadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 16:05:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">httpwww.dance.uw.edu/?p=13</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Colombia captain Catalina Usme is “dreaming big” and coach Nelson Abadia wants to “make history” as the last team standing from the Americas plots the downfall of England in the Women’s World Cup quarter-finals. The 25th-ranked South Americans have never made the last eight before but they are brimming with confidence after grinding down Jamaica [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Colombia captain Catalina Usme is “dreaming big” and coach Nelson Abadia wants to “make history” as the last team standing from the Americas plots the downfall of England in the Women’s World Cup quarter-finals.</p>
<p>The 25th-ranked South Americans have never made the last eight before but they are brimming with confidence after grinding down Jamaica 1-0 on Tuesday thanks to a goal from their skipper.</p>
<p>They will now play England in Sydney on Saturday and are fearless, having beaten world number two Germany in the group stage.</p>
<p>“Because of their football and their history we need to be careful, we need to be cautious,” Abadia said of Sarina Wiegman’s strongly fancied England.</p>
<p>“But in football we have already seen that the gaps between teams have been closing down and Colombia have proven to be a solid team.</p>
<p>“Of course, England are one of the favourites, that goes without saying &#8211; they are the European champions.</p>
<p>“But we also faced Germany, who were second favourites. We were wise enough and had the composure.”</p>
<p>Colombia’s intense, attacking mindset has served them well so far, with their teenage striker Linda Caicedo one of the stars of the tournament.</p>
<p>But Usme is the glue that keeps them together and she said they were in no mood to stop now.</p>
<p>“We want more,” she said, having scored the goal to take Colombia into the last eight.</p>
<p>“It’s not our ceiling, now we are thinking about England, which is going to be a dream match.</p>
<p>“We need to be calm, play an intelligent match, but with the certainty that we can achieve more in this World Cup.</p>
<p>“We are dreaming big &#8211; we can do this,” she added.<br />
Abadia has been in charge since 2017 and after failing to qualify for the last tournament in France, has nurtured the likes of Caicedo into the players they are today.</p>
<p>The 67-year-old has made no secret of their intention to at least reach the final and match the feat of Brazil in 2007, when they were runners-up to Germany.</p>
<p>No South American team has won the Women’s World Cup.</p>
<p>“When we qualified for the World Cup the first thing I said to my team is that we are not here just to spend some time &#8211; we want to make history and it is better to make history than to tell history,” he said.</p>
<p>“We have consolidated a very strong group, both for the technical staff and for the players.</p>
<p>“We brought the 23 best players from our country and we know how mature, how good they are.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>httpwww.dance.uw.edu/colombia-dreaming-big-as-they-plot-england-downfall-at-womens-world-cup/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Born in New York&#8217;s Bronx before dominating the globe, hip hop turns 50</title>
		<link>httpwww.dance.uw.edu/born-in-new-yorks-bronx-before-dominating-the-globe-hip-hop-turns-50/</link>
					<comments>httpwww.dance.uw.edu/born-in-new-yorks-bronx-before-dominating-the-globe-hip-hop-turns-50/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[paglaadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 16:03:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Entertainment]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">httpwww.dance.uw.edu/?p=10</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A genre, a culture and a lifestyle all at once: hip hop has traveled from the block party to the billionaire&#8217;s club, soundtracked protest and celebration, and asserted seismic influence over the course of pop. The reigning music style evolved in rapid, anarchic ways, rocking the industry establishment that long resisted its power, and fully [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A genre, a culture and a lifestyle all at once: hip hop has traveled from the block party to the billionaire&#8217;s club, soundtracked protest and celebration, and asserted seismic influence over the course of pop.</p>
<p>The reigning music style evolved in rapid, anarchic ways, rocking the industry establishment that long resisted its power, and fully embodying the culture of youth even as the genre grew up.</p>
<p>This year hip hop turns 50, an anniversary that&#8217;s offered its elders, its fans and the city that birthed it a milepost to reflect on its cultural weight.</p>
<p>The exact birthday is difficult to isolate, but the general consensus of musicologists and insiders is that on 11 August, 1973 hip hop&#8217;s rumblings came to a head in New York.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s the stuff of myth: DJ Kool Herc&#8217;s younger sister Cindy threw a back-to-school party in the rec room of 1520 Sedgwick Avenue, a high-rise apartment building in the Bronx near a major expressway.</p>
<p>The artist, born Clive Campbell in Jamaica, spun the same record on two turntables, legend has it, mixing the rhythms into the first documented breakbeat &#8212; an essential building block of the genre.</p>
<p>&#8220;It was just a birthday party, it was just a moment, you know,&#8221; Ralph McDaniels, a hip hop historian and pioneering TV host, told AFP. &#8220;But that party is the beginning and the spark that set off all of this for all the other DJs.&#8221;</p>
<p>The DJ offered fodder for the b-boys and b-girls &#8212; the partiers who developed breakdancing.</p>
<p>And then of course there&#8217;s the emcee: the master of ceremonies who rapped spoken word to the beat.</p>
<p>These types of house parties took place in a Bronx suffering some of the worst effects of nationwide economic turmoil that was particularly acute in New York.</p>
<p>Discriminatory housing and highway development caused mass displacement, economic decline and entrenched poverty in the borough.</p>
<p>Landlords burned buildings for insurance money rather than maintain them, as the city justified limiting public resources as it grappled with fiscal crisis.</p>
<p>The block parties and jam sessions were a lifeline for teens and families living in this bleak reality.</p>
<p>&#8220;I was a kid when it first started, and I saw how it brought the community together,&#8221; Jerry Gibbs, who grew up in the Bronx, told AFP.</p>
<p>&#8220;It was a special treat for us, having jams in the park. You&#8217;d see the DJs come out and how they hooked up the equipment and how they were creative with their music&#8230; They made people dance,&#8221; the 55-year-old, who now goes by the moniker DJ Cool Gee, continued.</p>
<p>&#8220;They made people forget about all their problems, all their issues, all their worries &#8212; for one night they was able to be on like a mental vacation.&#8221;</p>
<p>What&#8217;s now referred to as old-school hip hop began developing in the late 1970s into the early 1980s, as the music went from the block to the nightclub.</p>
<p>The classic DJ-MC live performance eventually saw the rap &#8212; the easiest element to isolate and package &#8212; go commercial and find resounding success.</p>
<p>But even as it flourished, hip hop&#8217;s stories remained rooted in experiences of injustice and inequality.</p>
<p>&#8220;Hip hop&#8217;s greatest artists came out of tough times,&#8221; McDaniels said. &#8220;The greatest artists like Jay, Biggie, Nas, I&#8217;ve been to where they grew up at.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;These are not great places, but they found love in that place,&#8221; he continued. &#8220;And they knew and understood the people, and the families and the people and the smells and everything that goes along, and the pissy elevators.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8220;And they took all of that color and stuff and put it in their records.&#8221;</p>
<p>&#8216;The heart&#8217;<br />
Into the 2000s, rappers including Kanye West, Jay-Z, Cardi B, Drake and Nicki Minaj were responsible for massive pop hits.</p>
<p>Yet no matter how big, how rich, how dominant hip hop grew, it maintained the aura of the underdog, the counterculture.</p>
<p>Year after year the Recording Academy faced backlash for failing to pay rappers their due, oft confining their Grammy wins to racialised categories.</p>
<p>But as the streaming age has taken hold and hip hop&#8217;s unmistakable global influence &#8212; from music to fashion, language to dance &#8212; has become clear, what&#8217;s also evident is that hip hop is more movement than genre.</p>
<p>&#8220;People weren&#8217;t really that accepting of hip hop &#8212; they thought it would fail,&#8221; said Paula Farley, 59, a Bronx native who started attending underground hip hop parties in her youth and returned to a recent celebration in the Bronx with Grandmaster Flash.</p>
<p>&#8220;As you can see, 50 years later, we proved them wrong.&#8221;</p>
<p>Even as the culture went global, for Farley, hip hop remains a New Yorker.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is the heart, right here, the Bronx,&#8221; she told AFP, as performers warmed up the stage ahead of a throwback jam featuring Flash himself, complete with a troupe of breakdancers and appearances from the likes of Melle Mel and KRS-One.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is the home of hip hop, the birth,&#8221; Farley said, as kids played in the deep summer heat, their parents and grandparents vibing to the beat.</p>
<p>&#8220;This is what it&#8217;s all about.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>httpwww.dance.uw.edu/born-in-new-yorks-bronx-before-dominating-the-globe-hip-hop-turns-50/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>NASA may delay crewed lunar landing beyond Artemis 3 mission</title>
		<link>httpwww.dance.uw.edu/nasa-may-delay-crewed-lunar-landing-beyond-artemis-3-mission/</link>
					<comments>httpwww.dance.uw.edu/nasa-may-delay-crewed-lunar-landing-beyond-artemis-3-mission/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[paglaadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 16:02:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Technology]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">httpwww.dance.uw.edu/?p=6</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[NASA&#8217;s Artemis 3 mission, set to return humans to the Moon in 2025, might not involve a crewed landing after all, an official said Tuesday. Jim Free, the space agency&#8217;s associate administrator for the Exploration Systems Development Mission Directorate, told reporters in a briefing that certain key elements would have to be in place &#8212; [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>NASA&#8217;s Artemis 3 mission, set to return humans to the Moon in 2025, might not involve a crewed landing after all, an official said Tuesday.</p>
<p>Jim Free, the space agency&#8217;s associate administrator for the Exploration Systems Development Mission Directorate, told reporters in a briefing that certain key elements would have to be in place &#8212; notably the landing system that is being developed by SpaceX.</p>
<p>Should that not be ready on time, &#8220;We may end up flying a different mission,&#8221; he said.</p>
<p>Under the Artemis program, NASA is planning a series of missions of escalating complexity to return to the Moon and build a sustained presence in order to develop and test technologies for an eventual journey to Mars.</p>
<p>The first, Artemis 1, flew an uncrewed spacecraft around the Moon in 2022. Artemis 2, planned for November 2024, will do the same with crew on board.</p>
<p>But it is during the Artemis 3 mission planned for December 2025 that NASA has planned its grand return to the Moon with humans for the first time since 1972, this time on the lunar south pole, where the ice can be harvested and turned into rocket fuel.</p>
<p>Elon Musk&#8217;s SpaceX has won the contract for a landing system based on a version of its prototype Starship rocket, which remains far from ready. An orbital test flight of Starship ended in a dramatic explosion in April.</p>
<p>Free said NASA officials had visited SpaceX&#8217;s Starbase facility in Texas a few weeks ago to &#8220;learn where they are with the hardware, trying to understand their schedule some more.&#8221;</p>
<p>Though he found the visit insightful, he said he remained concerned &#8220;because they haven&#8217;t launched,&#8221; and will need to do so multiple times before the rocket will be ready.</p>
<p>What&#8217;s more, delays to Starship have knock-on effects because the spacesuit contractor needs to know how the suits will interface with the spacecraft, and simulators need to be built for astronauts to learn its systems.</p>
<p>He added that NASA will update the public in the near future once it has had time to &#8220;digest&#8221; the information gathered during the Starbase visit.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>httpwww.dance.uw.edu/nasa-may-delay-crewed-lunar-landing-beyond-artemis-3-mission/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hello world!</title>
		<link>httpwww.dance.uw.edu/hello-world/</link>
					<comments>httpwww.dance.uw.edu/hello-world/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[paglaadmin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2023 15:58:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">httpwww.dance.uw.edu/?p=1</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to WordPress. This is your first post. Edit or delete it, then start writing!]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Welcome to WordPress. This is your first post. Edit or delete it, then start writing!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>httpwww.dance.uw.edu/hello-world/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
